Richard Symonds Collection of Connecticut Railroads Annual Reports 1988.0062
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Richard Symonds Collection of Connecticut Railroads Annual Reports
1886-1910
1988.0062
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
21.0 Linear feet
Collection consists of annual reports submitted by approximately 80 Connecticut railroads and street railroads to the State Railroad Commission and the Public Utilities Commission. Reports include brief histories of the companies, lists of company organizations, officer and property owners, track information, and financial data.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of annual reports submitted by approximately 80 Connecticut mainline railroads and street railroads, most of which are affiliated or owned by the New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad, to the State Railroad Commission and the Public Utilities Commission. The reports include brief histories of the companies, lists of company organizations, officer and property owners, track information, and financial data.
Provenance and Acquisition
The collection was donated by Richard Symonds in 1988.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
History
Richard Symonds is a resident of Tolland, Connecticut, and a collector of railroad documents.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to New England railroads. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Symonds, Richard. (Collector); Annual Reports.; Railroads - New England.; Street-railroads.
- Series I: Railroad Annual Reports Collection, 1886-1910
  - 1886-1910 (Box 1)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Boston and New York Air Line Railroad (1886-1906), Branford Lighting and Water Company (1902-1905), Bridgeport Traction Company (1894-1900), Bristol & Plainville Tramway Company (1895-1910), Central New England & Western Railroad (1890-1892), Central New England Railway (1899-1900)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 2)
    [Subjects include: Central New England Railway (1901-1910), Central Railway and Electric Company (1894-1898), Cheshire Street Railway (1904, 1906), Colchester Railway Company (1886-1905)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 3)
    [Subjects include: Connecticut Central Company (1886-1887), The Connecticut Company (1907-1910), Connecticut Lighting and Power Company (1899-1900), Connecticut Railway Lighting Company (1901-1910), The Consolidated Railway Company (1904, 1906), Danbury and Bethel Street Railway Company (1894-1910), Danbury and Norwalk Company (1886-1901)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 4)
    [Subjects include: Danbury and Norwalk Company (1902-1905), Danielson and Norwich Street Railway (1902), Derby Street Railway (1894-1901), East Hartford and Glastonbury Horse Railroad (1894-1905), East Windsor Street Railway (1910), Enfield and Longmeadow Electric Railway (1897-1900), Fair Haven and Westville Railroad (1894-1902), Farmington Street Railway (1900-1909), Greenwich Tramway Company (1902-1905), Groton and Stonington Street Railway (1905-1910), Hartford & Connecticut Valley Railroad (1886-1892), Hartford and Connecticut Western Railroad (1886-1892)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 5)
    [Subjects include: Hartford and Connecticut Western Railroad (1894-1910), Hartford and Harlem Railroad (1886-1887), Hartford and Springfield Street Railroad (1901-1909), Hartford & West Hartford Horse Railroad (1895-1898), Hartford, Manchester & Rockville Tramway (1895-1905), Hartford Street Railway (1894-1902)]
  - 1886-1906 (Box 6)
    [Subjects include: Housatonic Railroad (1886-1898), Manufacturers Railroad (1898-1905), Meriden and Cromwell Railroad (1886-1887), Meriden Electric Railroad (1895-1902), Meriden, Southington & Compounce Tramway (1889-1906), Meriden, Waterbury and Connecticut River Railroad (1889-1898), Middletown, Meriden & Waterbury Railroad (1899-1905)]
  - 1886-1906 (Box 7)
    [Subjects include: Middletown Street Railway (1895-1902), Milford Street Railway (1899-1900), Montville Street Railway (1900-1904), Naugatuck Railroad (1886-1905), New England Railroad (1896-1906)]
  - 1886-1905 (Box 8)
    [Subjects include: New Haven & Centerville Street Railway (1894-1998), New Haven and Derby Railroad (1886-1905), New Haven and Northampton Company (1886-1902)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 9)
    [Subjects include: New Haven and Northampton Company (1903-1910), New Haven Street Railway (1894-1899), Newington Tramway Company (1896-1906), New London & East Lyme Railway (1907-1910), New London Northern (1886-1904)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 10)
    [Subjects include: New London Northern (1905-1910), New London Street Railway (1894-1905), New York Air Line Railway (1886-1899), New York & New England Railroad (1886-1895), New York, Bridgeport & Eastern Railroad (1891), New York, Providence & Boston Railroad (1886-1892), Norwalk Street Railway (1894-1901), Norwalk Tramway Company (1894-1901)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 11)
    [Subject includes: New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 12)
    [Subjects include: Norwich and Westerly Railway (1907-1909), Norwich and Worcester Railroad (1886-1910), Norwich Street Railway (1894-1899), The Peoples Tramway, of Putnam, Connecticut (190-1902), Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad (1893-1896)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 13)
    [Subjects include: Philadelphia, Reading & New England Railroad (1897-1899), Portland Street Railway (1896-1898), Providence & Danielson Railway (1886-1909), Ridgefield & New York Railroad (1886-1909), Rockville Railroad (1886-1905)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 14)
    [Subjects include: Shelton Street Railway (1897-1900), Shepaug, Litchfield & Northern Railroad (1886-1898), Shoreline Railway (1886-1897), Somers & Enfield Electric Railway (1894-1898), South Manchester Light, Power & Tramway (1895-1910), South Manchester Railroad (1886-1894)]
  - 1886-1910 (Box 15)
    [Subjects include: South Manchester Railroad (1895-1910), Stamford & New Canaan Railroad (1886-1890), Stamford Street Railway (1895-1905), Suffield Street Railway (1902-1905), Torrington & Winchester Railroad (1898-1906), Waterbury Traction Company (1894-1898), Watertown & Waterbury Railroad (1886-1890)]
  - 1894-1910 (Box 16)
    [Subjects include: Westport & Saugatuck Street Railway (1894-1900), West Shore Railway (1894-1910), Willimantic Traction Company (1904-1905)]
  - 1894-1902 (Box 17)
    [Subjects include: Winchester Avenue Street Railway (1894-1902), Worcester and Connecticut Eastern Railway (1902)]